<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Mitchell Weggemans - Blog</title><link>https://MitchellWeg.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Mitchell Weggemans - Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://MitchellWeg.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using a REST API</title><link>https://MitchellWeg.github.io/using-a-rest-api/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://MitchellWeg.github.io/using-a-rest-api/</guid><description>What is REST? A RESTful API, mostly truncated to a REST API, is a way to communicate with your backend.
REST utilizes a number of methods. The most popular are: GET, POST, PUT, PATCH &amp;amp; DELETE
GET: The most common method. This gets a resource from the service.
POST: This creates a resource from on the service.
PUT: This creates or replaces a resource on the service. The difference between PUT and POST is that calling it multiple times has the same effect, meaning its idempotent.</description></item><item><title>Using MLFlow to version your ML models [Part 1]</title><link>https://MitchellWeg.github.io/using-mlflow-part1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://MitchellWeg.github.io/using-mlflow-part1/</guid><description>Preamble If you&amp;rsquo;ve doing anything with machine-learning in the past, you know how much of a pain it is to keep track of your models. When testing, you might have multiple versions of the same model just lying around, without knowing what parameters went into it to produce the result. MLFlow aims to tackle this issue.
Setting up MLFlow Before installing MLFlow, it is recommended to initialize a virtual environment first:</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://MitchellWeg.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://MitchellWeg.github.io/about/</guid><description>Who am I? My name is Mitchell. I&amp;rsquo;m a junior software engineer from the Netherlands with an interest in systems-programming, writing tools and scripts, and Artificial Intelligence.
In my short career I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated experience with a lot of programming languages. Most notably I use Rust, Go, C# and Python almost daily. These 4 are by far my favourite languages. I&amp;rsquo;ve also racked up some experience with C, C++, Java, Haskell, Bash, web-languages like PHP (&amp;amp; Laravel) &amp;amp; Java/Typescript.</description></item></channel></rss>