<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Statistics on Mitchell Weggemans - Blog</title><link>https://MitchellWeg.github.io/tags/statistics/</link><description>Recent content in Statistics on Mitchell Weggemans - Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://MitchellWeg.github.io/tags/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Analyzing Women's World Cup statistics with Statsbomb</title><link>https://MitchellWeg.github.io/statsbomb/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://MitchellWeg.github.io/statsbomb/</guid><description>Preamble Data is the new gold. And luckily, there is an abundance to be found if you just look for it hard enough. Nowadays, it is used virtually everywhere.
Today we&amp;rsquo;re gonna take a look at the open dataset provided by Statsbomb. Within this dataset, a lot of goodies are waiting to be discovered.
In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through on how to import and visualize the data.
The Code First, lets import Statsbomb:</description></item><item><title>The Statistical Significance of the NFL Combine - Part 2</title><link>https://MitchellWeg.github.io/combine-stats-part-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://MitchellWeg.github.io/combine-stats-part-2/</guid><description>Preamble After preparing the data in the first part, we can now start exploring the data we&amp;rsquo;ve created. To make it a little bit easier to run the code, I created a GitHub repository that includes a docker-compose that sets up everything you need to have a database and a Grafana dashboard.
The code can be found here. The README has extensive instructions on how to run everything.
Data exploration College Stats Lets first create a graph to see which college created the most NFL players: SELECT COUNT(college) as player_count, college FROM draft GROUP BY college ORDER BY player_count DESC;</description></item><item><title>The Statistical Significance of the NFL Combine - Part 1</title><link>https://MitchellWeg.github.io/combine-stats-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://MitchellWeg.github.io/combine-stats-part-1/</guid><description>Preamble Probably everyone has at least a dream of playing a professional sport at least once in their lives. Unfortunately, this is only for the the best of the best, and it&amp;rsquo;s pretty uncommon for us common folk to ever surpass the semi-pro level.
While my own chess rating barely exceeds the 1500&amp;rsquo;s, it&amp;rsquo;s always fun to look up at the pro&amp;rsquo;s, and with football that is no different.
The NFL combine is a way for the future stars of the NFL to impress the scouts, and possibly get an edge on their draft stock.</description></item></channel></rss>